bluepay.com 2015-09-06

# Privacy Policy | BluePay

Effective Date: 04/15/2015

This privacy policy applies to www.bluepay.com (“site”) owned and operated by BluePay Processing, LLC. This privacy policy describes how BluePay Processing, LLC collects and uses the personal information you provide on our web site: www.bluepay.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information.

BluePay Processing, LLC (“BluePay”) is committed to safeguarding the privacy and security of the information we collect. We have implemented multiple security measures to ensure the protection of your information including secure servers and networks that are accessible to a limited number of employees and industry standard encryption technologies when transferring or receiving sensitive information.

BluePay Processing, LLC has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at 866-739-8324. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this website, www.bluepay.com and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the site. and information that may be collected from AssureBuy Gateway.

**Collection of Information**  
When visiting websites, you provide information to the site owners based on where you go and what you do at each site. BluePay collects and retains this information for business purposes only. It is used to improve the quality and functionality of our site as well as to respond to requests for more information on all of the products and services we offer. This information is collected through Web server logs and cookies that allow us to track the aggregated statistics and data from our visitors as they utilize our website.

**E-Mail Lists**  
BluePay Inc, maintains e-mail lists to keep interested parties informed about our company, events, products, support, and more. E-mails are typically sent out twice per month, and contain valuable information for our merchants, agents, partners, and other interested parties. Our e newsletters often contain Web beacons, which collect information such as a cookie identifier and the time and date that the email was viewed or opened. They do not collect any private or identifiable information, but allow us to track how many people opened our e-newsletter. We do not sell the addresses on our list, but we may make information available to specific business partners, sponsors, or service providers.

Users may voluntarily request to join our mailing lists by signing up or opting in through the e-newsletter Sign Up form on our website. To be removed from our mailing list, simply email us now or click the unsubscribe link provided in each e-newsletter.

**Personal Information**  
We do not collect personal information from you unless you provide it to us in conjunction with an application for a merchant account or any other service we offer. The information collected such as your name, company name, credit card information, email address and phone number, is used for the underwriting, approval and set up required for the service you request. We do not license, sell, rent or trade any collected business information about your account or other personal information unless you request it, the information is provided to help complete a transaction initiated by you, or the disclosure is otherwise lawfully permitted or requested. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request, if BluePay is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information, to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

**Correcting and Updating Your Personal Information**  
To review, update or delete your personal information to ensure it is accurate, you may contact your sales representative directly, or you may contact us at 866.441.9670

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Additional Policy Information**  
Our website includes Widgets, which are interactive mini-programs that run on our site to provide specific services from another company (e.g. displaying the news, opinions, music, etc). Personal information, such as your email address, may be collected through the Widget. Cookies may also be set by the Widget to enable it to function properly. Information collected by this Widget is governed by the privacy policy of the company that created it.

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs and community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Our blog is also managed by a third party application that may require you to register to post a comment. We do not have access or control of the information posted to the blog. You will need to contact or login into the third party application if you want the personal information that was posted to the comments section removed. To learn how the third party application uses your information, please review their privacy policy.

With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us a CustomerService@BluePay.com.

**Third Party Links**  
In an attempt to provide increased value to our visitors we may have various third party websites link to our site. We do not control these sites and our Privacy Statement does not apply to them. These linked sites are for your convenience and your use of them is subject to each individual website’s Privacy Statement and Terms of Use. Please review the Privacy Statement from each of those websites before browsing them.

**Security**  
The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at CustomerService@BluePay.com.

**Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies**  
As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. We use persistent cookies. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. We use cookies to help us determine the referring site our visitors come from. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by BluePay and our partners [marketing partners], affiliates, or analytics or service providers [customer support provider]. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.htm>

**Behavioral Targeting**  
We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [Here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). . Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

(AdSense/Adwords) We use Google AdSense to publish ads. When you view or click on an ad a cookie will be set to help better provide advertisements that may be of interest to you on other Web sites. You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google’s Advertising and Privacy page: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html.

**Minors**  
BluePay does not market to or solicit data from minors. The services we provide are for businesses with owners and principals 18 years of age or older. At BluePay we value keeping information private and secure. BluePay is a member of the BBB (Better Business Bureau) Online Reliability Program.

**Notification of Privacy Statement Changes**  
We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**If you have any questions about this policy, please contact us at:**  
BluePay Processing LLC  
184 Shuman Blvd., Suite 350  
Naperville, IL 60563

We can also be reached via e-mail at [CustomerService@BluePay.com](mailto:CustomerService@BluePay.com) or by phoning us (toll-free) at **866.441.9670**.
